greenchange.org 2011-12-12

# What is the Green Change Privacy Policy? - Wiki - Show - network.greenchange

Green Change is committed to protecting the privacy of visitors to our website, as well as our members and activists. Green Change has established this Privacy Policy to explain what information we collect through this website and how it is used.

In this policy, “Green Change” refers to Green Change staff, board members, cooperating attorneys, interns, volunteers, and consultants, all of whom are bound by law or contract to keep information they receive as part of their assistance to Green Change confidential.

We encourage you to read our Terms and Conditions and Community Code of Conduct too. They describe many facets of Green Change that affect your privacy.

Unless otherwise specified, content published on Green Change is licensed under the Creative Commons 3.0 attribution unported license. For more information, go to [creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/](http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/)

> **Information Gathered by Green Change’s Site**

> For visitors to our website, we may, but generally do not, log standard technical information, such as the numerical Internet protocol (IP) address of the computer you are using; the browser software you use and your operating system; and the Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our site.

> Circumstances in which we temporarily log standard technical information include conducting site testing, diagnosis of technical problems, and defending against attacks on the site. We generally do log the date and time users access our site on an anonymous basis.

> We do not use persistent cookies on this site unless you log into the Green Change Network or use “Remember Me” or other similar functionality. We may use session cookies from time to time. Session cookies expire when you close your browser. You can set your browser to refuse cookies, and use Tor if you wish to keep your IP number and other technical information anonymous.

> In addition, Green Change collects and retains information you submit to us. It is up to you whether to submit information to us, and how much information to provide.

> If you choose to become a Green Change member, we ask for your name, email address and invite you to select a password.

> We also maintain records of our members’ use of the Green Change Network, and you may wish to indicate your particular interests and additional personal information in your profile.

> For online donors, we ask for your name, mailing address, email address, employer, occupation and credit card number. Employer and occupation are required for 527 political organization filings we must periodically send to the IRS. We cannot accept anonymous contributions.

> We may ask for additional personal information when you provide feedback or comments, or otherwise communicate with us.

> If you choose to subscribe to our free e-newsletter, we collect your email address and first name, and, if you choose to provide it, other personal information.

> From time to time, we may ask for personal information on other portions of the site, such as asking you to sign a petition or do an online action.

> **Green Change’s Use of Information**

> In general, Green Change uses the information provided by you to further its mission, transforming power and politics with Green values.

> Green Change does not sell or rent donor information under any circumstances, and we do not share information without prior consent except as compelled by law.

> We use member information to process and manage your membership or contribution. If you opt in, we will use your email address to send you updates and alerts, so you may take action, such as contacting your representative in Congress or attending an event.

> If you invite another person to join Green Change, we will ask for that person’s name and online contact information. We use this information to contact and, if necessary, remind that person that he or she has been invited to join Green Change.

> If you provide information for publication, such as suggesting a link, we may use your name to provide you with credit.

> We may run surveys, contests, or similar activities through this site. Such information will be used for the purposes for which it was collected.

> We look at technical information to diagnose problems with our server and to administer our site and network.

> **Third-Party Service Providers**

> Portions of the site are operated by a third-party service providers, which is currently Working for Change (WFC).

> WFC may place cookies on your computer in order to store information, such as storing your account login when you do an online action. WFC logs standard technical information, such as the numerical Internet protocol (IP) address of the computer you are using; the browser software you use and your operating system; the date and time you access our site; and the Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our site.

> WFC also stores and organizes the personal information collected through this site on our behalf. The information remains under our control, and our agreement with WFC requires the information to be kept confidential and disclosed only to Provider’s employees who require such access in the course of their assigned duties.

> Green Change may change the provider from time to time, and will transfer stored information to the new provider subject to similar restrictions.

> Green Change’s search capability is provided by a third-party search engine, which is currently Google. Information submitted to the search function is not collected by Green Change, but it may be collected by the search engine provider, subject to the search engine provider’s privacy policy. Green Change may change the search engine provider from time to time.

> From time to time, Green Change may work with third-party consultants or other service providers who may have access to personally identifiable information. In such cases, we will restrict their use of personally identifiable information in accordance with their assigned tasks and subject to the limitations of this privacy policy.

> Green Change’s site provides links to a wide variety of third-party websites. Green Change is not responsible for, and does not have any control over, the privacy practices or the content of such third parties. We encourage users to read the privacy policies of any website visited.

> **Disclosure of Your Information**

> While Green Change endeavors to provide the highest level of protection for your information, we may disclose personally identifiable information about you to third parties in limited circumstance, including: (1) with your consent; or (2) when we have a good faith belief it is required by law, such as pursuant to a subpoena or other judicial or administrative order.

> If we are required by law to disclose the information that you have submitted, we will attempt to provide you with notice (unless we are prohibited) that a request for your information has been made in order to give you an opportunity to object to the disclosure. We will attempt to provide this notice by email, if you have given us an email address, or by postal mail if you have entered a postal address. If you do not challenge the disclosure request, we may be legally required to turn over your information.

> In addition, we will independently object to requests for access to information about users of our site that we believe to be improper.

> **Updating or Removing Your Information**

> You may choose to correct, update, or delete the membership information you have submitted to us by sending an email requesting changes to membership@greenchange.org. Furthermore, if we inadvertently collect more personal information than intended, we endeavor to delete the extraneous information. However, please understand that deleted information may continue to persist on back-up media.

> **Changes to Our Policies**

> Green Change’s Privacy Policy may change from time to time. However, any revised privacy policy will be consistent with Green Change’s mission. If we make any substantive changes to our policies, we will place notice in our online newsletter and post notice of changes on this page.

> **Security**

> Green Change employs industry standard security measures to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. Information submitted through the shopping, membership, and donation processes is encrypted through a Secured Socket Layer (SSL) connections, which protects the information in transit.

> Although we make good faith efforts to store information collected by Green Change in a secure operating environment, we cannot guarantee complete security. Information collected by F will be maintained for a length of time appropriate to our needs. However, we generally do not retain credit card information unless you choose to have us make automatic monthly withdrawals from your account for your donation.

> Credits: Electronic Frontier Foundation
